<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rattle-textviews>
  <textview widget="summary_textview">UNIVARIATE DATASET SUMMARY

It is useful to understand how our data is distributed

The summary here will include more details depending on
which check buttons you choose. 

The Summary option provides a very brief summary.

The Describe option provides comprehensive summaries of each variable.

Kurtosis and Skewness allow these measure to be compared across
the available numeric variables.</textview>
  <textview widget="summary_textview">UNIVARIATE DATASET SUMMARY

It is useful to understand how our data is distributed

The summary here will include more details depending on
which check buttons you choose. 

The Summary option provides a very brief summary.

The Describe option provides comprehensive summaries of each variable.

Kurtosis and Skewness allow these measure to be compared across
the available numeric variables.</textview>
  <textview widget="playwith_textview">LATTICIST DATA VISUALISER

Latticist provides a graphical user interface for exploratory data visualisation. 

For the loaded dataset latticist attempts to produce useful displays
based on the properties of the data.</textview>
  <textview widget="ggobi_textview">GGOBI DATA ANALYSIS

GGobi provides a separate interface to perform highly dynamic and
interactive data visualisation.

Specialist tools include tours, scatterplots, barcharts and
parallel coordinates plots. 

Plots allow points to be identified and linked with
brushing across multiple plots.</textview>
  <textview widget="correlation_textview">NUMERIC VARIABLE CORRELATION

A correlation analysis will provide insights into how independent
the input variables are.

Modelling often assumes independence, and better models will
result when using independent input variables.

A table of the correlations between each of the numeric variables
will be listed, and a correlation plot will be displayed.</textview>
  <textview widget="hiercor_textview">NUMERIC VARIABLE HIERARCHICAL CORRELATION

Dendrograms provide a visual clue to the degree of closeness between variables.

The hierarchical correlation dendrogram produced here presents a view
of the variables of the dataset showing their relationships (correlations).
Depending on the data, you may find groupings of variables that are highly
correlated. These will be fairly obvious in most cases.

The length of the lines in the dendrogram provide a visual indication of
the degree of correlation (or the tightness of the correlation - shorter
lines indicate more tighly correlated variables).

Once you have identified the groups of variables that are correlated,
you may want to reduce the number of variables you are including in your
modelling.

Note that only numeric data is processed to produce the plot. Categoricals
are not handled by this analysis.</textview>
  <textview widget="prcomp_textview">PRINCIPAL COMPONENTS ANALYSIS

Principal Components Analysis can provide insights into the importance
of variables in explaining the variation found within the dataset.

Two plots will be displayed. The bar chart shows the significance of
each component, whilst the biplot remaps the data points from their
original coordinates to coordinates of the first two principal
coordinates.</textview>
  <textview widget="test_textview">STATISTICAL TESTS

These tests apply to two samples. The paired two sample tests assume
that we have two samples or observations for each entity, and that we
are testing for a change, usually from one time period to another.

DISTRIBUTION OF THE DATA

  Kolomogorov-Smirnov     Non-parametric    Are the distributions the same?
  Wilcoxon Signed Rank    Non-parametric    Do paired samples have the same distribution?

LOCATION OF THE AVERAGE

  T-test               Parametric        Are the means the same?
  Wilcoxon Rank-Sum    Non-parametric    Are the medians the same?

VARIATION IN THE DATA

  F-test    Parametric    Are the variances the same?

CORRELATION

  Correlation    Pearsons    Are the values from the paired samples correlated?</textview>
  <textview widget="kmeans_textview">KMEANS CLUSTERING</textview>
  <textview widget="hclust_textview">HIERARCHICAL CLUSTERING</textview>
  <textview widget="associate_textview">ASSOCIATION RULE ANALYSIS

Association analysis identifies relationships or affinities between
entities and/or between variables. These relationships are then
expressed as a collection of association rules. The approach has been
particularly successful in mining very large transaction databases. It
is also often referred to as basket (as in shopping basket) analysis.
</textview>
  <textview widget="rpart_textview">DECISION TREE MODEL

A decision tree model is one of the most common data mining models. It
is popular because the resulting model is easy to understand. However,
the ensemble approaches (boosting and random forests) tend to produce
models that exhibit less bias and variance than a single decision tree
</textview>
  <textview widget="glm_textview">LINEAR AND GENERALISED LINEAR MODELS

A linear regression model is the traditional method for fitting a
statistical model to data. It is appropriate when the target variable
is numeric and continuous.

The family of generalized linear models generalises the applicability
of the traditional linear regression to target variables with
distributions different to the assumed normal (gaussian)
distribution. The algorithm iteratively fits linear regression models
to the data after transforming the target variable to make it numeric
and continuous.

Generalized linear regression, applied to dataset with a numeric,
continuous target variable, will build the same model, using a
different algorithm.

The generalised linear regression algorithm is parameterised by the
distribution of the target variable and a link function which relates
the mean of the target variable to the input variables. Together,
these two parameters describe what we often refer to as a family. We
see in the interface a choice of families.

If the target variable has just two possible outcomes the target is
transformed using a logistic or probit function.  A probit regression
gives similar results to the logistic regression, but often
with smaller coefficients.
</textview>
  <textview widget="ada_textview">ADAPTIVE BOOSTING MODEL

The basic idea of boosting is to associate a weight with each entity
in the dataset. A series of models are built and the weights are
increased (boosted) if a model incorrectly classifies the entity.
</textview>
  <textview widget="rf_textview">RANDOM FOREST MODEL

A random forest is an ensemble (i.e., a collection) of un-pruned
decision trees. Random forests are often used when we have very large
training datasets and a very large number of input variables (hundreds
or even thousands of input variables). A random forest model is
typically made up of tens or hundreds of decision trees.
</textview>
  <textview widget="esvm_textview">SUPPORT VECTOR MACHINE MODEL</textview>
  <textview widget="ksvm_textview">SUPPORT VECTOR MACHINE MODEL

A Support Vector Machine (SVM) searches for so called support vectors
which are data points that are found to lie at the edge of an area in
space which is a boundary from one class of points to another. In the
terminology of SVM we talk about the space between regions containing
data points in different classes as being the margin between those
classes. The support vectors are used to identify a hyperplane (when
we are talking about many dimensions in the data, or a line if we were
talking about only two dimensional data) that separates the classes.
</textview>
  <textview widget="nnet_textview">NEURAL NETWORK MODEL</textview>
  <textview widget="confusion_textview">ERROR MATRIX</textview>
  <textview widget="risk_textview">RISK CHART

A risk chart provides an effective approach to presenting the performance of a model. 

The default chart displays caseload versus performance.</textview>
  <textview widget="confusion_textview">ERROR MATRIX</textview>
  <textview widget="lift_textview">LIFT CHART</textview>
  <textview widget="roc_textview">ROC CURVE</textview>
  <textview widget="precision_textview">PRECISION CHART</textview>
  <textview widget="sensitivity_textview">SENSITIVITY CHART</textview>
  <textview widget="costcurve_textview">COST CURVE</textview>
  <textview widget="pvo_textview">PROBABILITY VERSUS OBSERVED</textview>
  <textview widget="score_textview">SCORE

A model can be deployed on a dataset to obtain scores or
classifications for each entity in the dataset.

By default the testing dataset (if any) will be scored. Otherwise the
training dataset is scored. As an alternative, a CSV file can be
loaded and scored. This choice of what is scored is controlled by the
radio button options.

For binary models a probability score can be recorded. For regression
models a value is recorded for each entity. Otherwise a class will be
recorded for each entity. This can be controlled by the Class and
Probability radio buttons.

The resulting CSV file can include just those variables having a role
as Identifier, or else all of the variables.

The name of a CSV file into which the results will be written will be
prompted for.
</textview>
</rattle-textviews>
